Guide to the Office of the Vice Provost for the Arts Records, 1993-2012 UA.07.05.0002
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Office of the Vice Provost for the Arts records
1993-2012
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Office of the Vice Provost for the Arts.
UA.07.05.0002
2.5 Linear Feet
The Office of the Vice Provost for the Arts works closely with Duke arts departments, Duke Performances and the Nasher Museum of Art to expand and coordinate arts programming on campus. The Office of the Vice Provost for the Arts records consists primarily of promotional materials related to arts events and performances at or related to Duke, as well as some materials related to advertising or promoting performances, organizing events, and regional arts organizations.
Conditions Governing Access
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use of administrative records. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
Transfer, May 2015. Accession UA2015-0023.
Historical note
The Office of the Vice Provost for the Arts works closely with Duke arts departments, Duke Performances and the Nasher Museum of Art to expand and coordinate arts programming on campus. The office oversees the Visiting Artist in Residence program, organizes the annual Duke Arts Festival, and also works with the American Dance Festival and the Full Frame Documentary Film Festival to build strong arts collaborations between Duke and the local community.
The Vice Provost for the Arts is also a member of the Council for the Arts, which advises the Provost on policy and resource issues in the arts, promotes collaborative activity and interdisciplinary projects in the arts, and selects the recipient of the Sudler Award in the Arts. Scott Lindroth has been the Vice Provost for the Arts since 2007.
Collection Overview
The Office of the Vice Provost for the Arts records consists primarily of promotional materials related to arts events and performances at or related to Duke, as well as some materials related to advertising or promoting performances, organizing events, and regional arts organizations. Most of the promotional materials are brochures, programs, advertisements, and photographs; there are a small number of audio recordings. Other materials include emails, advertisment pricing and order forms, and newsclippings.
Dance -- Performance; Music -- Performance; Duke University. Office of the Vice Provost for the Arts.; American Dance Festival; Duke University. Institute of the Arts
- Vice Provost for the Arts Records, 1993-2012
  - Administrative Women's Network (AWN), 2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    AWN Annual Meeting pamphlet, booklets, "Care for the Caregiver" items
  - American Dance Festival (ADF), 1934-2008 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Annual reports, anniversary booklets, advertisements
  - American Dance Festival: Workshop, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Marketing plans, performance pamphlets/advertisements, newspapers, ADF and Chamber Arts Society booklets
  - American Rep. Dance Co., 2003-03-20 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Mar. 20, 8:00 PM, Reynolds. Pamphlets, curriculum guide, tour information, performance brochures
  - Arts Card, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Coupon sample, email copy
  - Arts in the Gardens, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Ticket order forms, information sheets, study guides, coloring sheets, article photocopies, newspaper clippings, advertisements
  - Arts Outreach: THRU the Nite, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Performance brochure, description, event proposal, event ticket
  - Arts Engagement: Future, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted until 2035
    Service-learning program overview, project budgets, program overview and goals, sheet of written notes
  - Arts Outreach/Engage, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    End of year report, information sheets, end of year gathering brochure
  - Arts-to-Go, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Restricted until 2031
    Email regarding budgeting, information sheet
  - Black Students Alliance, 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Graduation ceremony information, graduation booklet, program, final honors booklets
  - Calendar (1 of 2), 1969-2007; ` (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Arts at Duke newspapers, calendars of events, style sheets
  - Calendar (2 of 2), 1993-2006 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Calendars of events, arts around Duke newspapers, emails regarding advertising, participation lists/contact info, advertising contract
  - Brochures: Past, 1983-2008 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Duke University Artists Series brochures - performances and annual information
  - Chamber Arts Society (CAS), 1945-1995 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Fiftieth anniversary booklet, 44th/45th season brochures
  - Chamber Arts Society (CAS), 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Concert season booklets, performance programs
  - Chamber Arts Society (CAS), 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Performance programs, season booklet
  - Chamber Arts Society (CAS), 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Performance programs
  - Chamber Arts Society (CAS), 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Season booklets, performance programs
  - Chamber Arts Society (CAS), 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Chamber Arts Society (CAS), 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Season booklets, performance programs, subscription form
  - Chamber Arts Society (CAS), 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Season booklets, performance programs, photographs, usher/comp ticket lists, magazines, newspaper clippings
  - Chamber Arts Society (CAS), 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Restricted until 2027
    Season booklets, performance programs, performance group photographs, schedule, email confirming dates, draft of budget
  - Chamber Arts Society (CAS), 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Restricted until 2028
    Season booklets, performance programs, performance group photographs, newspaper article photocopies, Paris Piano Trio slides, concert performance list, budget, email regarding agents
  - Chamber Arts Society (CAS), 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Season booklets, performance group photographs, photo slides, performance programs, Finckel/Han press coverage booklet
  - Chamber Arts Society (CAS), 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Performance program, season booklet, repertory list
  - Chamber Arts Society (CAS), 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Season booklets, list of program offerings, newsletter (v.3, n.2)
  - Council for the Arts, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Meeting notes Nov. 2006
  - Duke Artist Series (DAS), 2000-2002 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Performance booklets, performance group photographs, comp lists, maps, article photocopies, photo slides, performance posters, information cards, performance brochures, newspaper clippings, biographical information, magazine pages
  - Duke Artist Series (DAS) History, 1930-2000 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    History booklets, 1995-96 season booklet, season performance dates lists, Duke Artist Series history by decade
  - Duke Artist Series (DAS): Luyala, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Performance postcards, performance informational newspapers
  - Duke Artist Series (DAS) Photos: University Photography, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Photo negatives in plastic protective sheets
  - Duke Artist Series (DAS) Playbills: Past, 1987-2002 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    History booklet, performance booklets, programs
  - Duke Arts, 2007-2009 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Restricted until 2034
    Copies of The Chronicle, performance dates sheet, sheet of handwritten notes
  - Duke Arts: Chronicle, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Copies of the Chronicle, newspaper clippings, renewal information, events sheets
  - Durham Arts Council, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Durham Art Walk information card
  - Duke Arts: Indy Ads, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Restricted until 2032
    Advertising contract, copies of Duke Arts newspaper, Duke Arts event sheets, brochure on advertising rates
  - Duke Arts: Indy, 2008-2009 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Ad renewal forms, Duke Arts event sheets, advertisement invoices, participating organizations list, list of fees/renewal forms
  - DART (Duke Arts), 2009 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    DART information cards/event lists, DEMAN poster, copies of The Chronicle, DART advertisement sheets,
  - Duke Gardens, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Duke Gardens Annual Report
  - Duke Moves, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Restricted until 2037
    FedEx receipt, festival advertisement sheets, Duke Moves newspaper, emails regarding budget
  - Duke: Old Duke, New Duke: William Willimon (Response), 2000 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Restricted until 2025
    Old Duke-New Duke Report to the President
  - Duke Performances (1 of 2), 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Anytown CD, performance programs, upcoming events booklets, Sleeping With Strangers CD, Timmy Abell at Duke Gardens CD, copies of the Herald-Sun, performance group photographs, performance advertisement sheets, online articles, performance posters
  - Duke Performances (2 of 2), 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Duke Performances media advisory information, performance programs, newspaper clippings, performance advertisement postcards, Duke University newspaper, clippings from the Herald-Sun, article photocopies, performance information sheets, performance advertisement sheets and posters, Duke performances booklets, subscription series sheet
  - Duke Performances (1 of 2), 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Newspaper clippings, newspaper photocopies, performance brochures, event advertisements, performance programs, sealed letter addressed to Duke Performances, Duke Performances press releases, events list brochure, articles, performance booklets, Duke Performances media advisory
  - Duke Performances (2 of 2), 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Season playbill, Quarter Notes booklet, performance programs, The Month at Duke newspaper copies, The Chronicle copies, event information sheets and advertisements, Duke Performances study guide for Master Storyteller, CAS season booklets
  - Duke and You, 1994-2002 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Duke and You newspaper copies
  - Durham Convention and Visitor's Bureau (DCVB), 1990-2006 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Official visitors guide, advertising contract and information, Durham Cime Comparative, Durham Brand Manual, Convention & Visitors Bureau memorandum, email regarding F&E Roundtable, Durham Official Visitors Guide
  - Durham Public Schools, 2003-2011 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Restricted until 2036
    Arts Education Advisory Council information and agenda, A Visual and Performing Arts School assignment/program information, mathematics curriculum, English/language arts curriculum kindergarten through grade 5, social studies curriculum, mathematics grade description from DPS DEPOT, science curriculum information, 2011 DPS Arts Resources Survey, article on Durham magnet schools
  - Ella Fountain Pratt, circa 2009 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Ella Fountain Keesler Pratt Legacy Project information
  - Herald Sun, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Restricted until 2030
    Advertisement reservation information, Holiday Songbook, Custom Publishing information book
  - Institute of the Arts (IOTA) (1 of 2), 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Restricted until 2029
    Performance information/advertisements, dialysis units search results, organ donation brochures and information, performance programs, printed news articles, performance posters, newspaper clippings, photo slides, pressbooks, performer photographs, Arts in the Gardens brochures, agreement form between Opera Carolina and Duke Institute of the Arts, press releases, parking information, NCMTA and Durham Music Teachers Assocation information
  - Institute of the Arts (IOTA) (2 of 2), 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Performance programs, performer photographs, performance advertisements, study guide for Samulnori, event announcement release, article photocopies, Holding Talks script and information, Grainne Murphy CD and photos
  - Institute of the Arts (1 of 2), 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Photo slides, report of ticket sales, performer photographs, performance advertisements, At the Hawk's Well National Tour 2002 Promotional Copy CD, performance programs, press reviews, magazine pages, articles, newspaper clippings,
  - Institute of the Arts (2 of 2), 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Newspaper clippings, artist information, articles, performance programs, performer photographs, photocopies of news articles, photo slides, performance advertisements, performance schedules, IOTA marketing plan, copy of the News&Observor, event brochures
  - Erol Josue, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Erol Josue performance advertisements, artist information, parking information, email regarding benefit concert, benefit concert advertisement
  - Claudio Valdes Kuri, 2003-02 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Feb. 19-20, 8:00 PM, Griffith. Performance programs, newspaper clippings, copy of the Herald-Sun Region, El Automovil Gris CD, Grey Auto notes, information for immediate release, performance advertisements
  - Leadership Durham, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Duke University Economic Impact Year 2003 Report
  - MLK [Martin Luther King Jr. Commemoration Committee], 2009-2010 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    African Children's Choir advertisements, AFC booklet, copy of The Chronicle
  - NC Dance Alliance, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Annual event brochure
  - North Carolina Presenters Consortium, 2004-2006 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Event dates and summary, On Stage North Carolina guide books, executive meeting outline, fall meeting questionnaire, advertisement information brochure
  - NC Symphony, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Concert book Feb-May 2005
  - NC Symphony, 2008-2009 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Sticky notes with handwritten notes, copies of The Chronicle, Duke employees discount information, marketing and publicity plans, event information for immediate release, sheet with handwritten notes, performance advertisements, checklist for Goodson Chapel usage, notes on meeting with NC Symphony, symphony emails and chapel reservation emails, artist information
  - NC Symphony, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Season book Sept-Dec 2008, tickets, magazine, performance information
  - The News Observer, 2001-2003 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Brochure options, CAS season booklet, NC Museum of Art membership information, newspaper clipping
  - Night Life, 1999-2001 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Copies of Night Life newspaper
  - Preview, 2010-2012 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Advertisement guidelines, Nasher Museum of Art schedules, performance and project flyers, copies of Duke Arts newspapers, copy of The Chronicle, copies of Preview
  - Photos: Artists, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Charlotee Blake Alston cassette, El Automovil Gris/Benshi in America CD, Arts & Engagement Project Fall 2008 CD, performer photographs
  - Photos: Campus Wide, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Photo slides, campus photographs
  - RAD (Representative for the Arts at Duke), 2003-2004 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Handwritten notes, RA@Ds lists, Representative for Arts @ Duke information sheets
  - Robertson Scholarship Program, 2005-2007 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Roberston Bus schedule, bus advertising reservations, email correspondence regarding Robertson Express Bus advertisements
  - SO Percussion, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    SO Percussion itinerary, Chereolab 2010 special offer information, responsibilities list, Chereolab information, Bam Study Guide for Imaginary City, copies of The Chronicle
  - THE STATE (magazine), 1993 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Copies of The State magazine
  - Summer Music (1 of 2), 1993-2003 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Bookmark, Summer Music Festival 2007 brochures, 2002 Summer Music Festival brochure, Summer Festival of the Arts information, performance advertisements and posters, performance programs, 1993 Summer Music Festival schedule, Summer Festival of the Arts information from 1994/1997/1999
  - Summer Music (2 of 2), 2002-2007 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    2003 Summer Festival of Chamber Music brochure, performance advertisements and programs, Summer Festival of the Arts newspapers, photographs, Summer Festival of Music brochures, newspaper clippings, Summer Calendar of the Arts copies, Summer Music in the Gardens brochures, copy of The Independent
  - Take A Stand, 2013 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Restricted until 2038
    Parking information, KidzNotes draft, KidzNotes schedule, sheets of handwritten notes, directions, email correspondence regarding ads and events, Regional Development Session information, marketing and publicity plans, Career Conference 2013 information
  - Urban Hiker, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Copies of Urban Hiker